Guide to the Andrew Forest Muir papers MS 017
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series V: Alphabetical subject research files, 1935-1969, 252462
  - Dueling, 19th century, 252911 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    Notes on duelists roughly in the Republic of Texas (1826-1856); AFM article "Dueling in Frontier Houston" (unpublished); notes taken from newspapers, printed sources, journals of the Texas Congress, acts of the Texas Congress, letter collections, district court records, published diaries, monographs, probate records, state records, journal articles, material of Dr. Chauncey Goodrich, Marcus Cicero Stanley, David G. Burnet, Gen. Hugh McLeod, John A. Wharton, William T. Austin, ____ Lynch, Ben McCulloch, Albert Sidney Johnston, Felix Huston, Mirabeau B. Lamar, W.S. Fisher, William Tinsley, Edward Burleson.
  - Duncan, Alexander, 252910 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Duncan, John Holt, 1820-1896, 252909 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    Resident of San Antonio 1856-1868 and Houston 1874-1895. Texas lawyer, Chief Justice of Bexar County (1850s), Confederate officer, district judge, recorder of City of Houston, Harris County Clerk.
  - Dunn, Joseph Wood, Rev., 252908 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    Episcopalian priest, missionary at Lockhart, Gonzales, Seguin and Bastrop, 1856-1857.
  - Dunn, Robert, d. 1902, 252907 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    Clergyman in Hawaii 1874-1876
  - Eaton, Benjamin, Rev., 1806/7-1871, 252906 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    Episcopalian priest, rector of Trinity Church in Galveston (1842-1871), missionary to Galveston (1841); notes on early organization of Episcopal Church in Texas (1840s), notes on history of Trinity Church (1840s-1850s).
  - Edwards, Monroe, 252905 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    Enslaver, Brazoria County, 1840s
  - Elkington, Joseph James, d. 1908, 252904 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    Catholic clergyman, Warden of the House of Charity
  - Empresario lawsuits, 1837-1840, 252903 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    Notes on the suits brought by S.C. Robertson, McMullin &McGlone, executor of Stephen F. Austin, R.M. Williamson, executor of James F. Perry and Samuel M. Williams, Jose Manuel Bangs and Haden Edwards against the presidents of the Republic to settle the rights and claims of empresarios after the Revolution (1837-1840).
  - Express companies, 1850s-1860s, 252902 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    Notes on company names, locations, Texas and Virginia, taken from newspapers.
  - Ewing, Alexander, 1809-1853, 252901 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    Surgeon General at Battle of San Jacinto
  - Eykyn, Thomas, 252900 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    Diocese of Honolulu, 19th century
  - Fish, John Fletcher, 252899 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    Episcopalian priest, U.S. Army chaplain at posts of San Antonio and Fort McKavett, TX, (1849-1850?)
  - Fish, John Fletcher, 252898 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    U.S. Army chaplain, 19th century
  - Fisher, George, 1795-1873, 252897 (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
    Attorney and political adventurer in colonial Texas, businessman and office holder.
  - Fitch, Carrie, 252896 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    Original correspondence with AFM regarding an essay on Carrie Nation.
  - Fite, Frank, 252895 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    St. Andrew's Cathedral, Honolulu, deacon 1901
  - Foster, W.T., 252894 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    School materials, 1940s, University of Texas
  - Fourier, Francois, 252893 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Free Negroes, 252892 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    Notes related to Texas and Alabama individuals and families, 1830s-1860s
  - Free Negroes in Texas 1827-1865, 252891 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Free Negroes in Angelina County, Texas 1860-1861, 252890 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Free Negroes in Bexar County, Texas 1851, 252889 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    Notes on Thomas Cevallos; official view of free Negroes in Bexar County (1851) taken from newspaper and laws of Texas legislature.
  - Free Negroes in Brazoria County, Texas 1822-1860, 252888 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    Notes on Greenbury Logan of Fort Bend County, Samuel H. Hardin, and others, James Richardson of Brazoria County; typescript with corrections of AFM article on Samuel H. Hardin; typescript with corrections of AFM article on Greenbury Logan (unpublished); notes taken from deed records, newspapers, probate records, civil district court records, land certificates, tombstones, criminal dockets, marriage records, journal articles, state records, laws of Texas, journals of the Texas Congress, manuscript collections, published letter collections, published primary sources, reference works; correspondence on research; material on George L. Hammeken; chronology of events in Texas 1861-1865; survey and abstracts of the "Telegraph & Texas Register" and "Morning Star" (Houston) on activities of the city council of Houston (1837-1845); materials of the city of Houston (late 1830s, early 1840s); letters with information on early Houston and the Port of Houston; notes on Henry Thuerwaechter; notes on George Lewis Hammeken from deed records of Limestone County (1833-1922); notes on Texas Supreme Court cases 1847; transcriptions of Sam Houston letters (1848, 1856); chronological lists of battles and actions in Texas in which troops of the regular U.S. army participated and troops engaged (1846-1854); notes on Enrique Mexia; AFM article "Lewis A. levy, Initiator of Organized Jewry in Texas" (unpublished)
  - Free Negroes in Fort Bend County, Texas 1838-1865, 252887 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    Notes on Peter Martin, Peter Nelson, Norman Davis, Nathan Burnett, and Oliver Brown, free Negroes of Fort Bend County (1838-1856); notes on Wyly martin, first chief justice of Fort Bend County; portion of AFM article on free Negroes in Fort Bend County.
  - Free Negroes in Galveston County, Texas, 1822-1859, 252886 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    Notes on free and emancipated Negroes in Galveston (1822-1859) taken from letter collections, printed sources, monographs, acts of the legislature, journals of the Texas Congress, newspapers, U.S. government records, deed records, Federal censuses, records of the district court, tombstones, will books.
  - Free Negroes in Grimes County, Texas 1839-1860, 252885 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Free Negroes in Harris County, Texas 1839-1860, 252884 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    Notes on 1847 suit of Emeline ____, memorials and petitions of free Negroes throughout Texas, Frank Burnes, Sulkey _____, Martha Moore, Delphina _____, Richard Robertson (drummer at Battle of San Jacinto), Eli Williams, Horace and Fanny ____, Thomas Savoy, Peter ____, Bob ____, Sally Vince, Maria Hamilton, Charlotte Dunn, Fannie M. McFarland, Ann Tucker, Dick Ellet, Diana Leonard, Zela (Zylpha) Husk, Nelly Norris, George William, Lucille ____, Maria ____, Tom Jefferson, Keziah ____, Sylvia Routh, Emily D. West, Amelia Raymond, Becky ____, Anderson ____, Richard Green, William White, Tamer ____ and Abby _____, Dick _____, Rhoda ____, George ____, Margaret _____, Matilda ____, Lyle ____, June _____, Bob Allen; notes from minutes of the county court, newspapers, army orders, correspondence, city records, legislative acts on free Negroes in general; correspondence on research.
  - Free Negroes in Jackson County, Texas 1835-1842, 252883 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    Samuel McCullock, Sr. and Jr. of Jackson County and their petitions to free black relatives in Alabama and Texas
  - Free Negroes in Jefferson and Orange Counties, Texas, 252882 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    Notes (1830s-1860) on members of the Ashworth family of Jefferson County, Hiram Bunch, Robert Wilson, J. M. Carter, William Nelson, T.K. Alexander of Orange County, residents of Panola, Polk, Red River and Refugio Counties; several copies of AFM article "The Free Negro in Jefferson and Orange Counties, Texas" (published); notes taken from Federal censuses, newspapers, pension papers, printed contemporary sources, laws of the Texas Congress, congressional journals, commissioner's court minutes, published diaries, Texas reports, district court records, probate records, deed records, comptroller's military service records, land grant applications.
  - Free Negroes in Matagorda, Texas, 1841-1855, 252881 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    Peggy Johnston, a free Negro in Matagorda County.
  - Free Negroes in Montgomery County, Texas, 252880 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    Notes on Maxlin Smith, Liney ____, and Adam Gautier, free Negroes of Montgomery County (1839-1841, 1859), taken from wills, pension papers, journals of the Texas Congress, newspaper, and district court records.
  - Free Negroes in Nacogdoches County, Texas, 1834-1857, 252879 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    Includes register of all free Negroes in Texas taken from 1850 Census.
  - Free Persons in Travis County, Texas, 1839-1858, 252878 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    Enslaved manumitted by William O'Connell (1858) and David Connor (1847) of Travis County; Henry Lynch, free Negro; John F. Webber, U.S. pensioner.
  - Flower, David Dubois, 252877 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    Episcopalian priest, rector of Christ Church (Matagorda) in the early 1850s.
  - Fontaine, Edward, 1814-1884, 252876 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    Episcopalian priest, former Methodist minister at Houston and Galveston (1840), private secretary to President Mirabeau B. Lamar (1841), rector at Austin (1851), army officer during the U.S. Civil War; Lamar Fontaine (son) author of "All Quiet Along the Potomoc" (?)
  - Freeman, George Washington, 1789-1858, 252875 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    Episcopalian priest, Missionary Bishop of the Southwest (Arkansas and Texas) in the 1840s, provisional Bishop of Texas (ante 1854-1857).
  - Gairdner, Meredith, M.D., 1809-1837, 252874 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Gallagher, Peyton, d. 1903, 252873 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Galveston ship registrations, 252872 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    Transcription of officials registrations, 1838-1840
  - Garrett, Alexander Charles, Rev., 1832-1924, 252871 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    Anglican priest, missionary to British Columbia (1860), educator, to San Francisco (1869), Bishop of Texas (1874); notes on Indians in British Columbia (1860s); two photographs of Garrett.
  - Geology, Texas, 19th century, 252870 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    Notes on a proposed geological survey of Texas conducted in 1858; records on the survey while in progress (1859); correspondence concerning the survey, progress reports, newspaper accounts and reference to survey and natural resources of Texas, legislative reports, legislative acts on the survey, early considerations by Congress for study of geology (1839-1840), William P. Huff and Texas fossils, artesian wells, office of state geologist, payroll of state survey (1859-1861), inventory of the state Geological Bureau (1861); part of AFM article on selection of State Geologist (1858); notes on State Geologist after the Civil War, Francis Moore, B.F. Shumard
  - Getchell, George Hermann, 1884-1922, 252869 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    Relative (?) and heir to George Hermann: 800 acre farm in Fort Bend County and building next to Rice Hotel, Houston. Murdered by his wife; property reverted to Hermann Hospital. Notes on his life and family.
  - Gilette, Charles, 1813-1869, 252868 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    Anglican priest, rector of Christ Church, Houston, 1843-1851. Survey of marriage bonds of Gonzales County (1829-1830); marriage records of Montgomery County (1838-1840).
  - Globe Chemical Company, 252867 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Gloyd, McNabb, 252866 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Godfrey, G.W., 252865 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    Episcopalian deacon at Trinity Church, Nacogdoches, 1850s.
  - Goliad (Walt Whitman on), 252864 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    Quotations from Whitman's Leaves of Grass concerning the Alamo, excerpts on the Alamo from "Song of Myself", criticisms of Whitman, other works of Whitman; correspondence on research.
  - Gonzales County, marriage bonds of, 1829-1838, 252863 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Goodwin, Hannibal, 252862 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    Diocese of California, rector of Grace Church, San Francisco
  - Goodwin, Henry Bradford, Rev., 1802-1859, 252861 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    Episcopalian priest of Maryland, missionary to Texas (1840), briefly rector of Christ Church, Houston in 1840; correspondence on research.
  - Goshorn, John Marshall, d. 1864, 252860 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    Episcopalian priest, missionary at Church of the Messiah (Gonzales, Texas) in 1859; rector of Trinity Church at time of his death. Died of yellow fever in Galveston, TX.
  - Gowen, Herbert Henry, 252859 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    Deacon
  - Gray, Edwin Fairfax, 252858 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    Graduated from the U.S. Naval academy 1852.
  - Gray, Peter William, 1819-1874, 252857 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    Member, Holland Lodge, 1844-1874. Lawyer of Harris County, state legislator, district court judge, Confederate congressman, associate justice of the Texas Supreme Court; notes on life and career; Milam Guards (1841-1842).
  - Gray, William Fairfax, 1787-1841, 252856 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    Diarist of revolutionary Texas, attorney, Founder of Christ Church, Houston; first clerk of Texas Supreme Court; district attorney under the Republic of texas; diary of Mrs. Milly R. Gray (1838-1840); Gray family; early Episcopal church in Texas; judicial system of the Republic.
  - Grayson, Peter William, Col., 252855 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Gregg, Alexander, 1819-1893, 252854 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    Episcopal priest, selected Bishop of Texas in 1859.
  - Groser, Charles Eaton, Rev., 252853 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Gulf Coast geography, 252852 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    Brief notes.
  - Haiti, 252851 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Hammeken, George Louis, 1811-1881 (1 of 2), 252850 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    Notes on his life, career, activities, family; the Union Land Company at Anahuac; photocopies of primary documents relating to the period of the Republic of Texas and Hammeken; notes on life and activities of Enrique Antonio Guillermo Mexia, his family; Hammeken as entrepreneur in Mexico, Texas colonist, agent of the Republic of Texas in Mexico, commission merchant (1840s), developer of transportation, President of the Brazos and Galveston Railroad Company; typescript copy of "Recollections of Stephen F. Austin" by Hammeken (1844); correspondence on research.
  - Hammeken, George Louis, 1811-1881 (2 of 2), 252849 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Handbook of Texas, 252848 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    Typescripts of AFM's contributions to the Handbook, edited by Walter Prescott Webb, 1952.
  - Hanna, Benjamin Franklin, 252847 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Hardesty, Mollie Arline Bailey, 1835/36-1918, 252846 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Confederate nurse and spy, circus owner; brief notes on life, career and family.
  - Hardin family, 252845 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Harris County, TX, 1822-1838, 252844 (Box 38, Folder 6-7)
    Notes taken from published letter collections, unpublished manuscripts, Spanish colonial records, journal articles, published primary sources, district court records, state records, deed records, probate records, records of the General Council, newspapers, United States territorial papers, records of the General Convention; pieces of AFM manuscripts; correspondence on research.
  - Harris County, TX, to 1837, 252843 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    Materials on the topic taken from Andrew Briscoe papers and papers of other Chief Justices of Harris(burg) County.
  - Harris County, TX, 1822-1866, 252842 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    Early Harris County general notes, research built around families and individuals.
  - Harris County, TX, 1822-1868, 252841 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    Surveys and transcripts of early records, correspondence, land surveys, etc. taken from deed records, minutes of criminal district court, minutes of county commissioners court, newspapers, census schedules, probate records, legislative statutes, letter collections, historical journals, marriage records, election records, proceedings of the board of land commissioners, published memoirs.
  - Harris County, TX, 1835-1839, 252840 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    Notes from government records on early settlers, place names, and government of Harris County taken from manuscript collections, election records, diaries, journals of the Texas Congress, state records, correspondence, congressional papers, published letters, deed records, journals of the Consultation, records of the general Council, newspapers, acts of the Congress, probate case papers, monographs, journal articles.
  - Harris County, TX, Commissioner's Court, 1837-1860, 252839 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    Survey and abstracts of minutes of Commissioners Court of Harris County, March 28, 1837 through May 28, 1860 (incomplete)
  - Harris County, TX, Deed records of, 1837-1846, 1857-1868, 252838 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    Transcriptions and reference notes, volumes A-K and S-Z.
  - Harris County, TX, District Court of, 1837-1867, 252837 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    Survey of minutes of 11th District Court, volumes A-H.
  - Harris County, TX, general, 252836 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Harris County, TX, index to probate cases of, 252835 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    Manuscript copy of the county index to Probate Cases, (probably) the earliest volumes.
  - Harris County, TX, Naturalizations in, 1837-1867, 252834 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    Survey of persons naturalized by county court of Harris County
  - Harris County, TX, Officials, 1836-1885, 252833 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    Lists of election results and officers for various county level offices.
  - Harris County, TX, Probate records of, 1836-1847, 1857-1872, 252832 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    Survey (incomplete) of Probate minutes of Harris County (Dec. 1838-June 1846) and survey (incomplete) of Probate Records of Harris County, volumes A-G (1837-1844) and L-T (circa 1857-1872)
  - Harris County, TX, Wills in, 1836-1858, 252831 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Harris County, TX, W.P.A. History, 252830 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    Typescript drafts of chapters by AFM
  - Harris, John Birdsall, 252829 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Harris, Lewis Birdsall, 1816-1893, 252828 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Harris, Samuel M., d. 1876, 252827 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Harris, Thomas, d.1907, 252826 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    Missionary, Honolulu
  - Hawaii, 252742
    Research on Anglican Church in Hawaii, often transcripts of newsclippings and letters.
    - 1779-1857, 252825 (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
    - 1858-1859, 252824 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - 1860, 252823 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - 1861, 252822 (Box 41, Folder 5-6)
    - 1862, 252821 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - 1863, 252820 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - 1864, 252819 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - 1865, 252818 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - 1866, 252817 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - 1867, 252816 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - 1868, 252815 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - 1869, 252814 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - 1870, 252813 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - 1871, 252812 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - 1872, 252811 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - 1873, 252810 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - 1874, 252809 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - 1875, 252808 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - 1876, 252807 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - 1877, 252806 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - 1878, 252805 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - 1879, 252804 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - 1880, 252803 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - 1881, 252802 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - 1882, 252801 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - 1883, 252800 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - 1884, 252799 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - 1885, 252798 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - 1886, 252797 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - 1887, 252796 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - 1888, 252795 (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - 1889, 252794 (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - 1820, 252793 (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - 1821, 252792 (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - 1822, 252791 (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - 1823, 252790 (Box 43, Folder 23)
    - 1893, 252789 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - 1894, 252788 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - 1895, 252787 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - 1896, 252786 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - 1897, 252785 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - 1898, 252784 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - 1899, 252783 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - 1900, 252782 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - 1901, 252781 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - 1902, 252780 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Archives of the Society / Propagation of the Gospel (transcripts), 252779 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Brittanica (encyclopedia) on Hawaii, 252778 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Church Chronicle, 1967-69, 252777 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Church in Hawaii (notes), 252776 (Box 44, Folder 14-15)
    - Cutts, Edward Lewes, 252775 (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Eastern Orthodox Church in Hawaii, 252774 (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - "Five Years' Church Work in the Kingdom of Hawaii", 1868, by Bishop of Honolulu, transcript, 252773 (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - Government records, 252772 (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - Government records, 252771 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Holiday Annual (undated publication? 1960s), 252770 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Honolulu Cathedral (plan and interior), 252769 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Iolani School, Honolulu, 1946-47 (includes photographs), 252768 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Lewis, Eric, 252767 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Newsclippings, 1867-1868, 252766 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Newsclippings and portions of publications, 1800s, 252765 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Notebooks, undated (1 of 2), 252764 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Notebooks, undated (2 of 2), 252763 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Notebooks, 1945: Honolulu, 252762 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Notebooks, 1946-47: Honolulu, 252761 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Notebooks, 1945-49: Honolulu, 252760 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Notebooks, 1947-54: Honolulu, 252759 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Notebooks, 1962-63: Honolulu, 252758 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Notebooks, 1964: England (1 of 2), 252757 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Notebooks, 1964: England (2 of 2), 252756 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Notebooks, 1965: Honolulu, 252755 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Patents, Hawaiian, 252754 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, 252753 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Queen Emma, Kaleleonalani (1836-1885), 252752 (Box 50, Folder 3-8)
    - Research correspondence, AFM, 1947-1951, 252751 (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
    - Research, general, 252750 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - St. Andrew's Priory and Cathedral, 252749 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Schofield Junior College, Schofield Barracks, Hawaii, 1947-48, 252748 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      AFM, instructor of American history and English
    - Searle, Cooper, 252747 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Sisterhood of the Holy Trinity, 252746 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Sisters Beatrice and Albertina, 252745 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Mark Twain and Bishop Staley, 252744 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Wills, 252743 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Hawkinses, 1835-1837, 252741 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    Note on Edmund St. John Hawkins, d. 1837 and George N. Hawkins, d. 1837, of Brazoria County.
  - Hayes, Rutherford B.: typescript of notes on Chapter 8, "The Trip to Texas", 252740 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Heath, Ebenezer S., 252739 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Hemphill, John, 1803-1862, 252738 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    Chief Justice of Texas Supreme Court, US Senator from Texas, Confederate States Senator from Texas.
  - Hemphill Family, 252737 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    Typescript with corrections of AFM article "John Hemphill, Miscegenist" (unpublished).
  - Henderson, Frances Cox, 252736 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    Wife of James Pinckney Henderson of texas, linguist, author. Notes on James Henderson and early Anglican church in San Augustine and Nacogdoches.
  - Henderson, James Pickney, 252735 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Hermann family: John (notes), Louis and George (images of), 252734 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Hervery, C.A. (Charles Amaleus), 252733 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Hill, William G. & Eliza M. Phillips Hill, 252732 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    References to the Hills in deed records, marriage records, probate records of Brazoria, Wharton, Colorado, and Galveston Counties, 1836-1879.
  - Hobby family, 252731 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    Genealogical research on Hobby and Pettus families of Harris County and Fort Bend County, respectively; family of former Governor William Pettus Hobby (1878-1964) and his father Judge Edwin Hobby (1842-1899).
  - Hogg-Swayne Syndicate, 1902, 252730 (Box 52, Folder 16)